Today we went to Cat Island, where more cats live than people!
We take a closer look at the reality of an island called a cat paradise!
First we take the train to get to Cat Island.
It takes about an hour to get to the destination station
We have arrived at our destination, Iyo Nagahama station
More ferry rides to get to the island
The boat makes two round trips per day. One way ¥700 ($5.27)
Small boats, so it seems to happen quite a bit in the winter when the waves are high.
Tickets can be purchased inside the boat
Tickets purchased for round trip
It takes about 30 minutes to get to Aoshima by ferry
There are no accommodations, stores, or vending machines at all on Aoshima, where we are going
So you will need to prepare food for your cat in advance
Cat Island in sight!
Where are the cats?
Ah! I found the cat!
Were they waiting for the boat to arrive? Two cats greeted me!
The skinship is very skinny!
I don't think he can see me.
It is said that there are now over 100 cats living on Aoshima
Famous cat island in Japan, many tourists visit the island every year
There are only a few places where you can feed the cats.
When we came to the feeding area, there were already many tourists and cats
Besides tourists, support groups are feeding cat food
Everyone is so enthusiastic about eating the food.
Their winter fur is so fluffy and cute!
Volunteers are giving water and food to the cats
The rule is to take all trash home and not overfeed them!
I'll follow the rules and feed mine.
Now for the memorial feeding!
Ouch！！！！
I got catpunched...
Ohhhh... my food...
I'm the one who wants to squeal...
And there was a fight going on nearby...
The cats are gathering in some parts of the area for food, which makes it easier for fights to break out
I'm going to break up the fight.
Looks like the white cat had the upper hand.
Let's feed the losing cat.
They're getting closer.
He's very wary, he won't come closer.
I'm going to move away a little bit.
I came to eat right away. Good, good, good.
Looks like you were quite hungry.
The other cats were approaching, probably sensing the food
He seems to have forgotten that he catpunched me earlier
Oh!!! Please be friendly with me!
Now I've been catpunched!
It's only been a few minutes since we landed, but a lot is happening!
Seems like we should feed them in several places.
They are all feeding well together, aren't they? Good.
There is a shrine on the island
The elevated location provides a panoramic view of Aoshima
Prayer.
May you get along well with the cats living on Aoshima...
One cat approaching!
Looks like my wish came true early!
They are very interested in the food I have!
Maybe it's not for me, but for the food?
I feel like they're asking me to feed them.
Unfortunately you can't feed them at the shrine
When I try to go down the stairs, he comes down with me
Very friendly natured cat. Cute.
I am very happy and will feed him again!
Brown, black, white cats, and other patterns are totally different!
I'm going to feed the cat that's quiet on the bench.
Another cat has come to eat
He's very concerned about it
But he doesn't sidestep. He's a patient boy.
I'll give it to him after he's finished eating now.
Ah!
I'm sorry. My bad.
It was my mistake to bring the cup.
Come on, eat a lot.
I want to feed the quiet cat, but the other cats are very strong
Cats seem to have different personalities
When you're done feeding them...
The cats started grooming
They are in relax mode
The last flight has arrived
If we miss this boat, we'll be in the field, so we'll come back tomorrow
We were only ashore for an hour, but we thoroughly enjoyed it!
If you want to fully enjoy the cats, I recommend coming on a morning flight!
If you live in Aoshima, you have to go shopping by boat, which is very difficult!
I'm staying at a guest house this time
Reservations are only made by phone in advance
Rooms are Japanese style and include breakfast and dinner for ¥7000 ($52)
The corridor is very cold, but the room is very warm and well heated!
The bath is also very safe, as if you were back in your parents' house
Dinner is moved to a ryotei restaurant a short distance from the inn
A private room with a TV for a very relaxing meal
And this is dinner! Gorgeous!!!!
Aji sashimi, fried aji, deep-fried aji, and side dishes... it's more gorgeous than you can imagine!
This is a great deal for ¥7,000 including lodging!
The sashimi is very fresh and very elegant!
Every dish is delicious!
If you come to Aoshima, this is definitely the place to come to eat!
After dinner, we buy cat food at a nearby supermarket
All this is cat food. A huge amount!
Tomorrow we will be on Cat Island all day, so we will buy more food!
I will also buy my own food for lunch tomorrow
Then I'm going to bed to prepare for tomorrow.
Good night...
Good morning...
Breakfast is very fresh and delicious rice!
When you come to Aoshima, you must stay here, breakfast and dinner included!
After checking out, we will head to the boat pier as soon as possible!
There seem to be fewer tourists on the morning flight
We were able to see the sunrise while on the boat
Good morning
Very early riser cat.
The fur is nice and fluffy
Oh!
The skinship is intense today too!
I was left behind again
How close are you guys?
A very soothing sight.
Still working on it...
Say hello to another cat
So cute!!! He came close to me!
Cats are nocturnal, but they are all already awake!
I wonder if they recognize me as someone who feeds them
They follow behind me.
It's breakfast time for the cats
More cats have gathered than yesterday
I feed them with both hands to prevent a fight from breaking out
That's it!
The chirping has stopped, and at once the battle for food has begun!
The volunteers are supposed to be feeding them, but they eat a lot of my food too!
My feeding has improved since yesterday.
I must have bought quite a lot of food, but I am going to run out in the morning!
No fights have occurred so far, so it's a relatively peaceful meal!
We feed the cats that can't get into the ring.
But other cats soon come and take the food
Let's give him some special high-grade food.
They look like they're eating well.
Ouch！！！！
It's not easy to feed them
Aoshima now has 100 cats and 3 residents
Residents are congregated near the boat dock, which is off limits to tourists for privacy reasons
We were not able to visit "Bentenzaki" at the tip of the island this time!
Tourists are prevented from entering.
The area near the feeding station is uninhabited, but access is limited due to the age of the building
Aoshima, which developed around fishing, had 889 inhabitants in 1942, but the population has been gradually declining and now stands at 3
There was a school in the past, but it is now closed and off limits
Looks like the cat has found something.
I'm going to try to follow it
What did you find?
I looked down there and didn't see anything
Oh my God. A fight has started
Looks like there is a cat in the clay pipe
I don't want to see as much fighting as possible, so I'll stop
Surely one cat is hiding in the back
It calms the other one down
When you are on an island, you often encounter cat fights
Even from a distance you can hear the cats fighting with each other
They fight throughout the night, so it makes a lot of noise for the people who live there
I thought cat island was supposed to be calm and relaxing, but the reality is different
The number of cats on Aoshima increased around 2013 when the number of tourists increased
The number of cats increased to more than 200 because tourists fed them a lot and they were unneutered and unspayed at that time
Interceding to prevent cats from fighting and falling into the sea
They gave up the fight and went away
They're gone. Good for you.
It's lunchtime, so we're going to have lunch
I decide to eat in the waiting room because the cats are likely to come if I eat outside
The waiting room is cleaned and very clean
Cats are not allowed in the building
I gently opened the door and found many cats waiting for me
Cute...
Wait a little while until you finish eating
Lunch is a half-price bento I bought at the supermarket last night
It is full of volume. Tempura of burdock
Is it a handmade bento? Very tasty.
It is fried horse mackerel. Aji is fresh and very tasty in Ehime.
The waiting room is decorated with many pictures of the former Aoshima
There are also remnants of a store that used to be there in the past
What are these drawers?
Oh! Lots of catnip in there!
I'm going to borrow one and play with my cat
Many cats were still waiting for me at the door!
Will they play with us?
Oh, wow!!! One of them responded!
Looks like he's having so much fun!
I couldn't find cat toys in the supermarket, so having them on the island would be very helpful!
I'll play with the other cats.
Huh? Is he responding?
Hmm?
There was a cat that was fighting frequently just now
It's all very tense at once
and here comes the arbitration
Here comes the cat with a lot of skinship
The air that was tense for a moment is now calm again
No reaction at all to the toys
We are back on peaceful Cat Island again.
Even the cat that fights so easily got on my lap! Cute.
I wanna play with those cats at the feeders too!
Oh!!! They're all sleeping.
Maybe we shouldn't force them to wake up
Currently all cats on Aoshima are neutered and no kittens are born
So most of the cats on Aoshima are older cats and eventually the cats will disappear from the island
Three of the residents are also elderly and have made the decision that there will be no one left to take care of the cats
Speaking of which, it seems that there is a famous cat on Aoshima that looks exactly like an anime character
They don't seem to be at the feeding station ...
He is an older cat and seems to rarely go outside
All the cats on the island are strays, so the residents don't know where they usually are
I met a resident and we had a little chat
The cat that looks just like the cartoon character is called "Dokin-chan" and does not show up at the feeding area!
And cats wearing collars are cats that are friendly to people and are all stray cats.
A resident helped us find "Dokin-chan" and brought her to us!
Finally, we meet Dokin-chan!
This cat is famous for its resemblance to the cartoon character "Dokin-chan"!
Elderly female cat that rarely goes outside.
She is a very beautiful cat!
She looks very comfortable after being out for so long!
I'm glad I came to Aoshima early in the morning...we met at the last minute!
It's a strange pattern, different from other cats
There was a cat flu epidemic in Aoshima and he was even hospitalized at one point!
He is now discharged from the hospital and is doing well in Aoshima, although his diet has become thin!
Residents, thank you for letting me meet you!
After a while, "Dokin-chan" left
The way she walks is graceful and dignified
I hope you will always be in good health.
We are also raising funds to protect cats in Aoshima!
Please help us!
Afternoon boats have arrived at Aoshima
The island is once again bustling with activity as many tourists arrive
Everyone is getting lots of food.
I'll give you all the rest of my food too.
Come on, come on! Come here! I've got food!
Oh the same cat ate me!
My first cat island was a calm and harsh reality similar to human society
Maybe people and cats are the same
Please come and visit Cat Island, everyone!
It was a very productive 2 days!
Thank you to the residents of Aoshima and their cats!
And thank you for watching this video to the end!
Where should we go next?